The birth of extreme
Dogtown and Z-Boys is a documentary film directed by Stacy Peralta.
This award-winning, thrilling story is about a group of discarded kids who revolutionized
skateboarding and shaped the attitude and culture of modern day extreme sports.
Featuring old skool skating footage, exclusive interviews and a blistering rock soundtrack, DOGTOWN AND Z-BOYS captures the rise of
the Zephyr skateboarding team from Venice's Dogtown, a tough "locals only" beach with a legacy of outlaw surfing.
Self, played by Jay Adams.
Self, played by Tony Alva.
Self, played by Stacy Peralta.
Self, played by Steve Caballero.
Self, played by Tony Hawk.
Self, played by Jeff Ament.
Dogtown and Z-Boys is a 2001 American documentary film co-written and directed by
Stacy Peralta, produced by Agi Orsi, and narrated by Sean Penn.
The documentary explores the pioneering of the Zephyr skateboard team in the 1970s (of
which Peralta was a member) and the evolving sport of skateboarding.
Using a mix of film of the Zephyr skateboard team (Z-Boys) shot in the 1970s by Craig Stecyk, along with contemporary interviews, the documentary tells the
story of a group of teenage surfer/skateboarders and their influence on the history of skateboarding (and to a lesser extent surfing) culture.
The film explores themes of skateboarding, 1970s, venice beach, california.
The tone is intense.